让我们用MATLAB来模拟整个彩色成像过程。
Let’s use MATLAB to simulate this whole color imaging process.
首先，我将再次为纳米单位创建一个简短的手。
To start with I am going to create again a short hand for the units of nanometers.
我将创建一个感兴趣的光谱区域，我将从中选择一个范围
I am going to create a spectral region of interest and I am going to pick a range from
350纳米，略高于我们在光谱的蓝色端看到的值。
350 nanometers, just above what we can see at the blue end of the spectrum.
以5纳米的步长，我将一直到800纳米。
In steps of five nanometers and I am going to go all the way up to 800 nanometers.
它只是在红色端的光谱可见端稍微超出一点点。
It is just a little bit beyond the visible end of the spectrum at the red end.
现在我要加载一些数据，这些数据是在地表测量的太阳光谱
Now I am going to load some data which is the spectrum of sunlight measured at the surface
地球和我们使用负载频谱功能我将在范围内传递
of the earth and we use the load spectrum function I am going to pass in the range
我感兴趣的波长，我将要求太阳能文件中的数据
of wavelengths I am interested in and I am going to ask for data from the file solar
点数据。
dot dat.
因此，这将太阳光的照射光谱加载到MATLAB工作空间变量中
So this has loaded the illumination spectrum of sunlight into the MATLAB workspace variable
叫做E，我可以用E对抗lambda并看看那里，我们有
called E and I can plot E against lambda and have a look at that and there we have the
底部的光谱波长和垂直轴的强度。
spectrum wavelength across the bottom and intensity on the vertical axis.
现在我要为着名的红砖加载反射信息。
Now I am going to load the reflectance information for the famous red brick.
再次使用负载频谱功能，通过相同的波长范围和
Going to use the load spectrum function again, passing the same range of wavelengths and
数据来自名为redbrickdotdat的文件。
the data comes from the file called red brick dot dat.
现在我可以在另一个图中显示，创建图二，现在我要绘制
Now I can display that in another figure, create figure two and now I am going to plot
R对抗lambda，在这里我们看到红砖的反射分布，我们可以看到
R against lambda and here we see the reflectance profile of the red brick and we can see that
它反射更多的红光然后它会发出蓝光。
it reflects more red light then it does blue light.
现在我可以计算出红砖的亮度，亮度就是它的乘积
Now I can compute the luminance of the red brick, and luminance is the product of the
照度E和反射率，我使用点星运算符，因为我要去的地方
illuminance E and the reflectance and I use the dot star operator because what I am going
要做的是将E中的每个元素乘以R.E和R中的相应元素
to do is to multiply every element in E by the corresponding element in R. E and R we
可以看到91是1个元素向量，我们可以看到的产品L也是91
can see are both 91 by 1 element vectors, and the product L we can see is also 91 by
1个向量。
1 vector.
现在我可以绘制照度，我们可以看到它看起来像这样;所以我们有来了
Now I can plot illuminance and we can see it looks like this; so we have the incoming
光，有这个频谱。
light, has got this spectrum.
从红砖反射出来的光有不同的光谱
The light that has been reflected off the red brick has got a different spectrum, it
已经反射出更多的红色，它吸收了更多的蓝色和绿色。
has reflected more red and it has absorbed more blue and green.
现在，我们将加载人类视锥细胞的响应，我也得到了这些信息
Now, we are going to load the response of the human cones, I have also got that information
在工具箱附带的文件中。
in a file that is shipped with the toolbox.
我们再次传入我们感兴趣的光谱范围，我们要求提供数据
Again we pass in the spectral range we are interested in and we ask for data from the
fileconesdotdat。
file cones dot dat.
现在有三个锥体，所以锥体数据是一个有91行和3行的矩阵
Now there are three cones, so the cones data is a matrix that has got 91 rows and three
列，每列对应一个锥体。
columns, each column corresponds to one of the cones.
第一列是红色圆锥，第二列是绿色圆锥，依此类推。
Column one is the red cone, column two is the green cone and so on.
我可以绘制锥形反应;再一次，我打算将它们与lambda和这里联系起来
I can plot the cone responses; again, I am going to plot them against lambda and here
我们看到三个圆锥响应，见蓝色圆锥，绿色圆锥和红色圆锥。
we see the three cone responses, see the blue cone, the green cone and the red cone.
现在我要做的是绘制红锥对这个入射光的响应。
Now what I am going to do is plot the response of the red cone to this incoming light.
现在我要做的是获取亮度，然后我将它乘以红色通道
Now what I am going to do is to take the luminance and I am going to multiply it by the red channel
锥体响应，所以我将在第一列的锥形响应中取所有行。
of the cones response, so I am going to take all rows in the cone response in column one.
这是包含有关红色圆锥的信息的列，这里我有它
That is the column that contains information about the red cone and here I have it, this
是红色圆锥对来自红砖的入射光的响应。
is the response of the red cone to the incoming light from the red brick.
锥体响应此函数的积分，即此曲线下方的区域，
The cone responds to the integral of this function, the area underneath this curve,
我们可以看到这条曲线达到峰值约0.18。
and we can see that this curve peaks up to about 0.18.
让我们来看看绿色锥体的含义，所以我现在改变那个数字
Let’s look at what it would be for the green cone, so I change that number there and now
我们看到这是绿锥的反应。
we see this is the response of the green cone.
峰值略低，峰值现在约为0.11;它不是很高。
The peak is a little bit less, the peak is now about 0.11; it is not quite high.
它是下面的区域;此曲线是绿锥观察时的响应
It is the area underneath; this curve is the response of the green cone when looking at
红砖。
the red brick.
最后，蓝锥的响应由此给出，我们可以看到这是
Finally, the response of the blue cone is given by this and we can see that this is
反应相当低，峰值仅为0.005。
a fairly low response, the peak value is only 0.005.
现在我可以使用一些来计算曲线下方区域的简单数值近似
Now I can compute a simple numerical approximation to the area underneath the curve using some
矩形整合。
rectangular integration.
使用MATLAB求和函数，我将亮度乘以响应
Use the MATLAB sum function and I am going to sum the luminance multiplied by the response
第一个例子。
in the first instance.
我将做红锥的响应，因为它是矩形积分
I am going to do the response of the red cone and because it is a rectangular integration
我应该适当地乘以波长步长，即
I should properly multiply by the wavelength step size, which is
5纳米，这是红锥的响应。
5 nanometers, and this is the response of the red cone.
绿锥的响应就是这样。
The response of the green cone would be this.
几乎一半的值和蓝色锥体的响应是这个小得多的值，
Almost half the value and the response of the blue cone is this much smaller value,
红锥对该亮度响应的响应约为八分之一。
about one eighth the response of the red cone to this luminance response.